This is an overview of Building Data
Products, which is a
sort of unique class that talks about,
what do you do
with the data analysis or the R functions
that you've created;
once you've built them, and you want to
share them with somebody else.
So, we'll be talking about things like R
packages,
how you build them, develop them and share
them.
This is one of the best ways to get your
name out there as a data scientist.
One of the main ways that people decide
about people to hire or
who to go after is whether they
built something that those people use
themselves.
And so, R package is the best way to get
your name out in that way.
We'll also talk about how to make
interactive graphics with things like
rCharts and how to make interactive apps
with things like Slidify and Shiny.
So, R packages you can think of it
as sort for the engineers; it's, you're
going to build
an R package to share code that you
allow other people to use to improve their
analysis.
So, we're going to teach you how to build
those; we're also going to teach
you how to use rCharts; you can think of
this is like for
marketing, build graphics, interactive
graphics like
you see in the New York Times
it'll allow you to share information that
can be interacted with by other people.
And then, finally, Shiny, sort of for end
users, you
can now use R itself to build web
applications that are
quite intricate and involved and allow you
to just interact with
data or interact with your analysis in
novel and unique ways.
So, we'll talk about all of these things
in Building Data Products.