In week two of course, we're going to be
covering a bunch of software that you're
going
to install that will constitute the data
scientist's
toolbox, as we described it for this
course's track.
So the first question you might ask
yourself is, what software do you need?
Well to know what, software you need, you
have to
know what exactly a data scientist is
going to do.
So, in this course sequence we're going to
talk
about all the different components of
being a data scientist.
So we're going to start with defining a
question of interest, and then
identifying the ideal data set try to
ident, to answer that question.
Determining if that data is even
accessible, a
lot of times the ideal dataset isn't even
available.
Then ways that you can go out and actually
obtain the data whether it's from a
database, or from a website, cleaning the
data
up so that it can be processed and
analyzed.
Performing some sort of exploratory
analysis,
including making plots and clusterings so
you
can identify patterns that you didn't know
about before hand in the data set.
Performing statistical prediction or
modeling to try to, build a sort of
an intuition about what's going to happen
in the next sample you might take.
Interpreting your results, challenging
them.
Then synthesizing them and writing them up
in
reproducible ways that can be shared with
other people.
Finally, we're going to talk about
distributing results
through things like interacting graphics,
also through
right ups and presentations, and finally
through
interactive apps built on top of R.
So the main workhorse of data science in
terms
of this data science track is the R
programming language.
There are other alternative languages that
are
also really great for data science, but
we're
going to be focusing on R, since it's one
of the most widely used languages.
And it's widely supported by a large group
of developers.
Who can contribute new packages all the
time
that can improve and extend the
functionality of R.
We'll be installing this in the second
week of the class.
We'll do most of our coding in RStudio.
RStudio is an Integrated Development
Environment, an IDE for R.
It's actually one of the best IDE's I
think for
many other languages as well in terms of
data science.
The R IDE is free as well just like the
language R, and so we
will be downloading this IDE and setting
it up again the second week of class.
The interface looks something like this.
And we'll talk a lot more about this in
the
second week and later on in the rest of
the class.
But you can see here in the top left-hand
corner I've got a file.
So this is a new .R file that's going to
contain some code that we're going to be
writing in.
So we can write that code, here in the
file
at the prompt and then down here, you see
a console.
So we'll be entering sort of a commands
at the command line down here in this
console.
And then over here you can see other
information you might be interested in
looking at.
See plots you recently made, the packages
that you have loaded,
or help files for specific functions that
you might be interested in.
There are a lot of other really nice
functions that come
with Rstudio, and we'll be talking about
those more throughout the class.
The primary type of file that we'll be
interacting with,
for the most part in this class, is an R
script.
So, an R script is a file with the
extension
.R, and so it's just a, actually a text
file.
Except the text file contains bits of R
code, so here it's you can see a comment.
So this isn't actually executed but R you
could include
that so that people can understand what's
happening in the code.
And then there're things like functions
and so forth which
we'll be talking about a lot more when
we're coding.
If this seems intimidating to look at this
function right now
you should worry about it when you get
through R programming.
You'll be a wizard and be able to do
things much more complicated than this.
The other thing that we'll be using is R
markdown documents.
So, reproducible research involves
creating documents that can be reproduced.
In other words, they can be rerun and
produce the
exact same numbers that you got when you
did your analysis.
And the primary vehicle for doing that is
through markdown and R markdown.
So this is a file with an extension ,RMD
and
this .RMD file has a very structured
format of text file.
And so we'll talk a lot more about what
that format is later but you
could take this structured file and you
can knit it to html with this button here.
And you actually create an html file that
will actually be formatted very nicely.
So for example, what you type in text
looks like this, and
it turns into a nice bulleted list in
HTML, once you knit HTML.
And we'll talk a lot more about how that
file works later in the class.
We're going to talk about how we are
going to
do distributed version control with Github
and Git.
So, part of this class will be setting
up your Github account and creating a
portfolio, of
all the different things that you do
throughout the
course track, that then you can share with
employers.
Or you can share and contribute to other
projects, so that
you can get your name out there in the
data science community.
We're going to running most of the
commands
from the shell or from the command line
interface.
So this is a command line interface, it
doesn't look like much right here.
You can see that there's a prompt up her
in the top left.
And we're going to be entering commands as
text prompts.
And those commands will then execute,
allowing
the programs that we're going to be
talking about.
So, there's a brief tour of all the tools
that we're going to be using in this
class.