This lecture is about getting help.
This lecture applies both to this cla-,
this course
that you're taking right now, the Data
Scientist Toolbox.
But also to all the other courses you're
going to be taking in the course track.
So, keep in mind that in a standard class
you may have taken in a
class of 30 or 100 people, you would raise
your hand and ask a question.
And then you'd be able to immediately get
feedback from your instructor.
But in a class like this in a massive
online open
class there could be up to a 100,000
people taking the class.
And what you're going to do instead is
post your questions to the message board.
And then hopefully, your fellow students
will upload them if they're good
questions.
And you instructor will try to respond to
as many as possible, but
probably more often than that your peers
or community TAs will be responding.
And so, there are three of us that are
teaching these nine classes and we
are going to try to put in as much as we
can to answer your questions.
But obviously, that's a limited resource.
And so relying on your fellow peers and
your community
TAs, we found is a great way to get
involved.
We've also learned that the community
that's built around the
message boards and the massive online open
courses is amazing.
And it's a, probably the best learning
part of the entire experience.
And so hopefully, you'll get involved and
you'll
be an active participant in those message
boards.
It's very clear that the fastest answer is
often the one that you find for yourself.
So to try to answer your questions
yourself, you should try to
look it up on Google or look it up on
Stack Overflow.
If you ask a question that's very simple
to Google, you'll
often a get response that says Google it
or read the documentation.
Which is not the easiest way to get the
answer that you're going for.
An important part of being an active
participant
in a community environment here is to, if
you figure out an answer to a question is
to post it to the message board.
If you're struggling with a particular
part
or structure or idea or art programming
exercise.
It's almost a sure bet that there's a lot
of other people that are struggling with
the same thing.
And so, they'll really appreciate it if
you take the time to post
the message board the way that you figured
out how to solve that problem.
So, I thought I'd mention just a few
important R functions that will
help you to find answers for some of the
questions you might have.
So, when you have an R function, we'll
talk a
little bit more about R more later in the
class.
You can actually type several different
ways you can
type to get the help file for that
function.
So, one example is that you can type like
this.
You can type ?rnorm and that will tell you
what the help file is for the function
rnorm.
You can also search like this help.search.
And if you use help.search, you might not
even
necessarily have to get the function name
exactly right.
It'll still search through, through the
help files and try to find things for you.
And then, if you want to get the arguments
for a function,
you can use the function, you can use,
the, command args, like this.
Args of rnorm and that'll tell you the
function arguments.
These functions are very useful if your
goal is to try
to figure out how r is working for a
particular function.
But it might not be so useful, if you want
to understand the sort of underlying
concepts involved in those functions.
So another thing is you might want to do
is
actually look a little bit deeper into the
code.
So if you wanted to do that you can
actually just type the function
name without any brackets and it will
actually reproduce the entire code for
you.
And so what you see here if I type rnorm
like this.
Then what I end up getting out on the R
console is actually this right here.
I get out sort of all the code that
corresponds to that function.
You could also see this link here to a
reference card with a lot of helpful R
functions.
So, an important point that you'll run
into a lot
in this class is how to ask an R question.
And so there are a few different
components
of it that you should keep in mind.
First is, you will want to outline what
are the steps
that you have executed in order to create
this problem.
So, if you ran three functions in order
you should reproduce what those three
functions are.
And then you should say what you expect
the output to be.
And then what you saw instead.
So I expected it to give me the answer
to this question and instead, it gave me
an error.
And so a really important thing to keep in
mind is that R packages and R and all
of these other tools that we're going to
be
telling you about are going to be evolving
over time.
And so it's really important that you tell
the version of the product that you're
using.
So, the version of the package, the
version of R
that you're using and then what operating
system you're working on.
Whether you're on Mac or Linux or Windows.
When you're asking a data analysis
question, there's a similar
set of things that you need to re, re,
report.
So first is what is the question you are
trying to answer.
You're saying I'm trying to relate
variable y to variable x.
And then, what steps or tools do you use
to answer it?
This may be a combination of R tools and
outside tools and maybe some intuition.
And then, you again, you report what you
expected to see.
I expected to be able to tell the
relationship between them and what do I
see instead?
I see oh, I don't know, I see some
crazy scatter plot and I don't know what
that means.
And so important thing to think, keep in
mind here
too is what other solutions you might have
thought about.
So sometimes you run through three or four
different things to try to get the right
answer.
And so, if you're report what you try or
the different things you try, there
when people try to answer your question,
they
can go directly to something you haven't
tried.
So an important point of asking questions
in
highly massive class like this is to make
sure
that you're very specific in the titles of
the questions that you're using on the
message forum.
So some examples of bad titles are things
like this.
So you can say, Help!
I can't fit a linear model.
Then you're not exactly giving a lot of
detail as
what exactly your problem is or how it can
be addressed?
So, a better question to ask is, sort of
saying, okay, I
have this function and it's happening in
that version of R 2.15.
And here is the error that's being
produced.
It's a seg fault that's being produced.
And is only being produced when I have a
large data set and here's the software
that I'm using.
I'm using Mac OS X 10.6.3.
And even better question is to use a title
that's a little bit more succinct.
So, here you lead off again, the function
that you're asking about, you
say okay, I'm asking about R 2.15 and
again it's on this operating system.
And then I very succinctly describe seg
fault on large data frame.
So by focusing on the very specific
details, it means people
can jump very quickly to the answers that
you might need.
So there's similar sorts of questions,
specific details you would
want to give when asking questions about
data analysis problems.
So, in general, the more specific you are
the faster your answer will come.
So there's some etiquette that we would
like
to encourage in terms of using these
forums.
Or in, in just using help sites in general
not necessarily the ones in these forums.
So, again, describe the goal that you
have.
What's the question you're trying to
answer?
Be very explicit.
Try to provide the minimum amount of
information.
If you, you provide way to much
information it's very hard for
people to filter through and figure out
what their real problem is.
Being polite never hurt anybody and will
often get your answer more quickly.
And then follow up and post solutions.
So if you post a question and somebody
ends up giving
you the answer on Stack Overflow instead
of on the course website.
It's the polite thing to do, post that you
found on the course
website so that people can search it and
find that answer as well.
Please, please use the forums rather than
using personal emails.
We are very excited about trying to help
you learn about data science.
But it's very easy to overwhelm the
inboxes of your
instructors or community TAs if you all
start sending emails simultaneously.
When there's a typo in the assignment,
please report it on the
forums and we will address it as fast as
we possibly can.
Some things that you shouldn't necessarily
do are immediately
assume you found a bug in a major program.
So, saying you found a bug in R and that's
why things aren't working.
Groveling as a substitute for your work is
obviously not a great thing.
So begging other people to do your work
for you.
Please don't post homework questions on
mailing lists or on the course forums.
If you post the questions or the answers
on the forums
it, it sort of takes away from the
experience of everybody else.
Please don't e-mail a lot of different
lists all simultaneously.
Try to figure out what the right mailing
list is and only e-mail that.
And then, you don't want to ask general
data analysis questions on R forums.
Those are often redirected back to
courses.
So try to keep those who are R course
forums, where hopefully there'll
be a big group of interested people all
trying to answer the same questions.
So the transfer of these slides go to
Roger Payne who's another instructor in
the course track.
He has these getting help videos.
That's a link to his video on YouTube and
it was
inspired by Eric Raymond's lecture, How to
ask questions the smart way.