This is the Getting and Cleaning Data
course overview.
This is actually one of the more unique
classes in our data science track, but
I think its sort of one of the
most fundamental components of being a
data scientist.
Which is being able to go out and get
data from whatever source it's in and
whatever form
it's in, and turning it into a clean
processed
data set, that then you can use to answer
questions.
So in this class, we'll be talking about
raw versus tidy data, how to download
files.
Reading in data from a very large number
of
different sources, merging it together,
reshaping it, summarizing it,
and then finding some data resources that
you can
use to augment the data that you already
have.
So here are a couple of different things
that you might learn about.
So, for example, how to connect to a MySQL
database, a MySQL database, from R.
So this is actually using an R package to
go to R MySQL,
and you'll be able to connect the
databases and read data from that.
Another idea would be sort of merging data
together.
So you take different components of a data
sets.
So there might be one cloud that contains
reviews and one cloud that
ca, contains solutions, say from a peer
assessment, and you want to combine them
together.
And so, you can use commands in R to merge
those data sets together.
And then, talking about, sort of, raw
versus processed data.
So talking about, what are the data that
come to you in their
rawest possible form, the original source
of the data versus the processed data.
The data that's ready for analysis, ready
to be
used by people that has happened after
you've merged
it, and sort, subsetted it, and
transformed it into
the nice tidy data set that people can
use.
So that's getting data.