In this video, I'm going to to briefly
show how you can install R on the Mac.
It's a very simple process.
You just have to, it only takes a few
steps.
So the first thing you need to do is open
your
web browser, and go to cran, says the
comprehensive R archive network.
So you can just type in cran here, [SOUND]
and you'll see that, [COUGH] there are a
number of options for you to
download here for different platforms, and
so
we're going to download the Mac platform
here.
So we go to download R for the Mac.
And you see that the latest version here,
is version 3.0.3.
You want to download this package file
here, so just click on
this, and you'll see that the download
meter will start going.
And it might take a few minutes depending
on the speed of your internet connection.
So just be patient.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, so its finished downloading.
So I'm just going to open up here, the
package and you can see it'll start the
installer.
Uh,and it'll guide you through all the
steps you need to install R 3.0.3.
So, I'll click continue here, and this is
just the description of what's going to
get installed.
Click continue.
The software license agreement is the
[UNKNOWN] new general public license
version 2.
So you should agree to the license, after
having read it of course.
And then, you can just click install here,
and
you might have to type in your
administrator password.
So, just go ahead and do that.
[SOUND] And it'll start installing the
files on your computer.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[SOUND].
Now that's finished, I can hit close, and
then it'll be in my Applications folder.
So I can just go to my Applications
folder,
which is right here, and there alphab,
alphabetic order.
So, I'll just scroll down to R, and there
it is.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And there you have it.
You have an R, installed R on your
computer,
and now, you can go ahead, you can just
use it directly, or if you want to you
can install, an interface like R studio,
if you like.
[BLANK_AUDIO]