This is a review of exploratory data
analysis,
which is the next course in the course
sequence.
Exploratory data analysis course will
cover the principles of how do
you create analytic graphics, graphics
that allow you to analyze data.
It'll talk about exploratory graphs, how
you explore the data and get in,
create enough graphs to sort of figure out
the structure of what's going on.
It will talk about the plotting systems in
R.
So it'l talk about base plotting, lattice
plotting
and then ggplot2 which is a popular newer
platform.
It'll talk about hierarchical clustering,
K-means
clustering and a little about dimension
reduction.
These are all techniques that you can use
to
get in and explore data as a first pass.
So, for example, it will talk about how to
use ggplot2 package to make plots like
this, sort
of, sort of pretty smooth scatter plots
that allow
you to like understand the relationship
between different variables.
It will talk about the principles of
analytic graphics,
so what are the principles that you need
to create
graphics that'll be useful sort of to
figure out what's
actually going on with the data you'll be
working with.
And then it'll cover things like K-means
clustering.
So the idea of how do we, if we have a
bunch
of observations of collecting data on
that, how we cluster them into
relative groups that are similar to each
other as a method of
exploring the data and figuring out the
structure of what's going on.
So this is just a couple of the
ideas that will be covered in exploratory
data analysis.