Statistical Inference is going to be a
course that covers many of
the foundational ideas that are involved
with extracting generalizable information
from data.
And so, the course will cover things like
basic probability,
likelihoods common distributions,
confidence intervals,
hypothesis tests, bootstrapping and power.
These are the sort of fundamental ideas
that you
often hear coming up when people are
reporting data analysis.
So, for example, we'll talk about sort of
the
way that you model mathematically coin
flips or proportions.
We'll also talk a little bit about how you
model more continuous
distributions, things like, with the
normal
distribution which you've probably heard
about.
As a way to measure sort of the
variability about a large
number of different things including IQ
and height and things like that.
And then we'll talk about things like
bootstrapping, where you
actually use the data itself to sort of
create measures of
variability that you can use to sort of
decide how generalizable
are the answers that you get from
performing any particular analysis.