This is an overview of practical machine
learning.
There are a large number of machine
learning
classes out there, and they are often very
good.
So, the focus of this class will be
primarily on hand-drawn application of
machine learning in R.
So, the idea being that we'll try to focus
on the R packages and the
ideas that will allow you to actually take
data and perform machine learning on those
data.
We'll also talk a little bit conceptually
about each of these prediction
methods work and maybe some of the cases
where there might be trouble.
And then we'll point you to resources
where you can learn more in depth about
the mathematical details or the really
hardcore
computational underpaying of these
methodologies if you're interested.
So the Practical Machine Learning Content.
We'll start with prediction study design,
we'll talk about cross validation.
The caret package for prediction in R,
some pre-processing.
Predicting what the variety of different
ideas like regression and trees.
We'll talk about common ideas like
boosting, bagging,
model blending, and a little bit about
forecasting.
So here are some examples of things we'll
cover.
We'll cover basic terms, like what are
true positives and false positives?
What are true negatives and false
negatives,
sensitivity and specificity, those sorts
of things.
We'll also cover how to deal with
correlated
predictors by preprocessing out data that
had correlated predictors.
When we're moving them from the training
data
set, and we'll talk a little bit about
boosting.
So, this is a very more technical machine
learning idea, but can be applied
quite simply using the functions of a R to
really improve your prediction accuracy.