[BLANK_AUDIO]
In this video, I'm going to talk about how
to install RStudio for the Mac.
It's a very simple process and only
involves just a few steps.
The one thing I'll say though is that you
must have R already installed before you
can install RStudio.
So, once you've installed R already.
You can go to the RStudio website, which
is Rstudio.com.
[SOUND].
And you can see down here on the lower
left, there's
a green button that that directs you to
kind of download RStudio.
So, here there's two versions of RStudio,
studio that you can download.
One is for the desktop and one is for the
server down here.
Now you, we're not going to be talking
about the server version at all here
so, you just want to download the desktop
version, so that's this button right here.
So the website should detect automatically
what
type of operating system your running, so
here I'm running a Mac, and so it
recommends this Mac OS X version.
So, I'm just going to download that right
now.
And, you'll see the download meter go.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Once that's finished downloading you go to
the Downloads folder, and it should be
the most left thing here so we're just
going to click on it to install it.
And then just like any other Mac
application, all you have
to do to install is drag it into the
Applications folder.
So, I'm going to do that right now.
And it's already done.
So, I can just go into the Applications
folder here and find RStudio.
Double-click on it [SOUND].
I'll say yes, I want to open this
application.
And there you go.
You're running RStudio.