One of the most widely used tools for
performing any
sort of statistical or data science
analysis is a regression model.
So the next course will be covering those
regression models.
Some would say it's just one other form
of just pre, creating a supervised
predictive function.
But it's a little bit more than that in
that it's, one of the more
interpretable and easily used, tools that
you
can use to sort of explain you analyses.
The people that are outside of the data
science community.
And, as communication is a critical
component of data science,
that makes regression models a critical
component of the tool box.
So, this course will cover linear
regression
and multiple regression, ideas like
confounding which
we'll see a little bit in this class even,
some prediction using linear models.
Scatterplots smoothing its splines, and
then
resampling inference, and maybe weighted
regression.
So, this will cover also some ideas
including ideas that you hear
about often when you read articles about
statistical analyses in the popular press.
Things like regression to the mean.
So, why is it that children of tall
parents tend
to be tall but not as tall as their
parents were?
So these sorts of fundamental ideas will
be explained in the regression class.
So we'll also talk a little bit about the
basic regression
model, there'll be a little bit more
mathematics in this class
than there are in some of the other
classes and sort
of deriving and understanding the basic
ideas behind a regression model.
But calculus and the new algebra are not
required.
We've worked hard to make it so that,
basic
understanding of algebra is sufficient to
follow this class.
We'll also learn about multivariable
regression analyses so,
sometimes you want to relate one variable
to another
variable but you want to account for, what
happens
when you include other variables,
adjusting your analysis.
You often hear about adjusting the
analysis, and
that will be covered in this class as
well.