Reproducible research is another one of or
more unique courses.
So reproducible research is concerned with
creating code
and documents that will completely
reproduce all of the
analysis that you've done in a transparent
way
so that you can communicate that to other
people.
It's one of the most fundamental
components of being a data scientist.
But it's often glossed over as a sort of
a side component of many other programs of
data science.
So we're going to talk about in the
reproducible research course, the
structure of a data
analysis, how do you set it up, how do you
organize it and put it together.
We're going to talk about some of the
components of reproducible
research in terms of programming which
include Markdown, LaTex, R Markdown.
And then we're going to talk a little bit
about a unique idea called evidence-based
data analysis, doing data analysis based
on
what's best practices in the field right
now.
And then ways that you can publish your
data outside of your own organization,
things like RPubs.
So for example, we're going to talk about
the steps
in a data analysis or in a data science
problem.
And so, you have to go all the way from
defining the questions
to creating sort of reproducible code that
you can share with other people.
And so, some of these steps are covered by
different parts of
the class, and so reproducible research
synthesizes where those parts go together.
We'll also talk about which files are
components of a data analysis.
Everything from the sort of a raw data to
the
exploratory figures to sort the final
analysis that you'll be performing.