[BLANK_AUDIO]
One of the things that we ask you to do in
this course a lot is to install software
from various places.
However if you use OS X Mavericks you'll
note it, you may notice that the default
installation has a couple of security
settings that
prevent you from just installing software
from the web.
This is meant to protect you from
installing kind of bad or malicious
software.
But it can also prevent you from, from
installing things like RStudio and other
pieces of software.
So in order to change those settings it's
fairly simple.
You go to the Apple menu here.
And you click on System Preferences.
And then you want to go to Security &
Privacy.
And by default you won't be able to make
any changes
before you, unless you type in your kind
of administrator password.
So I'm going to click on the lock here,
type in my password, and now you
can see that there are a number of
options here for, for downloading and
installing apps.
So the safest option is to only allow, you
know, applications from the Mac App Store,
but there
are many things that we, you'll need to
download
for this course that aren't in the Mac App
Store.
So you need to click on the Anywhere
button.
That will allow you to install software
from the web or from anywhere.
And as long as it you, and it's your
responsibility to kind of, make sure that
the software is okay.
And so you'll need this to install things
like RStudio and GitHu, GitHub.
And other pieces of software.
So that's how you do that on the Mac.