[BLANK_AUDIO]
I just wanted to briefly describe how to
install R for a Windows machine.
So the first thing you need to do is
load, launch your web browser, so I'll do
that here.
I'm using Chrome but it doesn't really
matter.
And you need to go to the Comprehensive R
Archive
Network, or CRAN, so I'll just type that
in here.
And
you'll see that there is a, at the top
there's three options, there's Linux a Mac
and Windows.
So you can go to the Mac version here,
and you want to go click on the base link
here.
And very top you'll see download R 3.0.3
for Windows and that's
exactly what you want so you can just
click on this link.
And the download will start, and so,
depending on how
fast your internet connection is, this
might take a few minutes.
Okay, so the download's finished.
I'm going to click on this.
And you'll probably have to click on Yes
for this.
And so, you can choose your language here.
There are a number of choices in terms of
the translations that you can choose from.
So I'm going to choose English because
that's my language.
And then you can just click through the
installer, it'll kind of walk you through
the various steps.
And so we'll do that right now just to see
what the options are.
So you click on Next.
You have to agree to the license, which is
the gener, the GNU General Public License.
So feel free to read it and then click on
Next.
Then usually the default installation
directory is fine.
So I'm going to go through this.
The Use the Default User Installation is
fine.
There are other kind of installation
setups that you can choose from.
If you know you only, you have a 32 bit
machine
it maybe an older machine you may, you can
click on that.
By default it will install both versions
so
you don't have to really worry about that.
So just click through Next on this one.
And can you choose, but it's just going to
take all
the defaults or you can try to customize
the start up.
I'm going to customize the start up just
so you can see what the options are here.
So this option here shows you whether,
asks
you whether you want an MDI, or SDI
interface.
So what that means is basically do you
want R
to kind of run in one big window with kind
of
different sub windows within inside of a
big window, or
you want it to run in kind of like
separate windows.
I prefer to use the SDI mode where the, so
the console will be
in one window and the kind of graphics
window will be a separate window.
I just kind of, I feel like a, I like
that a little bit better, it's easier to
work with.
So I'm going to click on the SDI option.
And then you can choose how you want to
look at your help files.
So the HTML Help is, is a little bit
nicer, it's prettier to read.
And the Plain Text Help is well it's just
plain text.
So maybe I'll just click on Plain Text
just to be different.
And then you can choose whether you want
Standard or Internet2 internet access.
This, generally speaking, you should not
mess with, so you just click on Next.
You can create a shortcut in the Startup
menu, Start menu so it's usually a good
idea.
And you can usually choose the defaults
here in your terms of creating a
desktop icon unless your desktop is very
cluttered and want to you know, avoid
that.
So these are, these defaults are fine, so
I'll click on Next.
And then it'll start installing the files
on your computer.
So now it's done.
If we can just click on Finish here.
And, and you've now installed R on your
computer.
And so I'll just close this browser here.
And I see you've got, I've got a
desktop icon here, so I'll just
double-click on that.
And there we are, we're running R.